<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ggseg-suite</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/ggseg-suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/ggseg-suite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;R-Packages&lt;/strong&gt;: A set of packages for visualizing brain atlas data in R.
The packages create the possibility of visualizing brain atlas data directly in 2d fully inflated brains or brain slices through ggplot2, and as 3d mesh plots through plotly.
They are intended to create easier workflows for researchers working in R and neuroimaging, reducing the need to switch between software too often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Igloo theme</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</guid>
      <description>This is a theme for creating a website theme for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator. The Hugo Igloo
theme is the theme of my website and created using UIkit 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and the Tidyverse for working with data</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/tidyverse_carpentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/tidyverse_carpentry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;: How to work efficiently with datasets in R using the Tidyverse, a Carpentries-style workshop.
The workshop is intended to be interactive, was initially developed to be run as a webinar, and can be expanded to single or two whole day workshop.
The workshop is intended both for R beginners as well as intermediate R users who know base-R well but wish to learn more about the Tidyverse way of working with data.
At the end of the workshop you will have a grasp of the Tidyverse way of working with data, and have learned new ways of efficiently working with data in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quartaki - Introduction to Quarto</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/quartaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/quartaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;: A 6 hour introduction to Quarto for report generation in R. Combining code with prose to create reports in a seamless environment. This workshop is taught with RStudio and R, but learners proficient in other compatible languages are welcome to join.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
