<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Igloo theme</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</guid>
      <description>This is a theme for creating a website theme for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator. The Hugo Igloo
theme is the theme of my website and created using UIkit 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, New blog</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</guid>
      <description>New year, a new blog, and some reflections on the past year that has passed . I&amp;rsquo;m taking the lead for a new Core Facility at the University of Oslo . I also got funding from my university to establish a Hub/Node network, which is an initiative from University IT to facilitate exchange of knowledhe between University staff .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reorganising Hugo Content and Aliasing</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Aliasing is a stickler for good organisation of content . Reorganising Hugo Content and Aliasing has a nice way of dealing with that, which they call [gohugoioio] Reorganisation concept is that people should redirect to the specific page that they should be using .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Actions to Build your Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Using GitHub Actions is a service that runs Continuous Integration, meaning that using a set-up file you can ask workers (computers run by GitHub) to do certain operations on your repository at certain triggers (at push, pull-requests or even on a schedule with crontab) This is where GitHub Actions shines. It is free and so are its actions for small jobs like what we want to do . To build on Netlify, you need all your content version controlled, in my case with git, and stored on GitHub . This is fine and dandy for text files like markdown, csv data, and images that &lt;em&gt;will not change often&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing your Blogdown Workflow</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Blogdown is usually used with [go hugo], a static webpage builder . Blogdown renders directly from &lt;code&gt;Rmd&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;html, meaning it circumvents hugo&#39;s processing of &lt;/code&gt;md` . This can cause some unwanted issues depending on your theme . It can also make it difficult to maintain your webpage over time .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
