<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2025 20:21:54 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Igloo theme</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</guid>
      <description>This is a theme for creating a website theme for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator. The Hugo Igloo&#xA;theme is the theme of my website and created using UIkit 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New year, New blog</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on the past years, I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on significant career milestones, volunteer work, and a new website revamp. Highlights include leading a new Core Facility at the University of Oslo, attending Posit::conf 2023, contributing to R-Ladies, rOpenSci, and R-Hub communities. My new Hugo Igloo theme offers a fresh look for my website.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reorganising Hugo Content and Aliasing</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Revamping a website and organizing content can be challenging. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I restructured my blog posts into yearly subfolders using a Bash script, added Hugo aliases for seamless redirects, and simplified file slugs for cleaner URLs. This automation ensures better content organization and link integrity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Actions to Build your Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Learn to build Hugo websites using GitHub Actions and deploy them with Netlify. This guide covers setting up GitHub Actions to build your site, install dependencies, render Rmarkdown files, and deploy to Netlify or GitHub Pages. Enhanced control and maintenance for your site, with step-by-step instructions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing your Blogdown Workflow</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Updating my hugo setup on netlify took over a year of delays due to complexities. After extensive work, I transitioned from knitting &lt;code&gt;.html&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;.md&lt;/code&gt;, fixed theme issues, and resolved netlify CSS problems. Follow my step-by-step guide to smoothly update your blogdown website. Learn to make use of hugo&amp;rsquo;s page bundles, adjust configurations, and ensure seamless rendering both locally and on netlify. This guide addresses key changes you might face, from altering your workflow to understanding theme changes and troubleshooting rendering issues.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
