<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hugo on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hugo on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Igloo theme</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</guid>
      <description>This is a theme for creating a website theme for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator. The Hugo Igloo
theme is the theme of my website and created using UIkit 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, New blog</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</guid>
      <description>A new year, a new blog, and some reflections on the past year</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reorganising Hugo Content and Aliasing</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working on a little website revamp, and on that occasion I have been thinking through some reorganisation of the file content of my website.
I&amp;rsquo;m a stickler for good organisation of content, and I was feeling that my blog folder was turning unruly. While it was nice machine readable and sorting well etc, it was just not&amp;hellip; nice for a human in the long run. I needed something different, something to soothe my organisatory heart.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Actions to Build your Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Lately, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing some work in getting Hugo websites building through Github actions, and then have them deployed with Netlify. Of course, once we are building with GitHub actions we could also just use GitHub pages to deploy, and I&amp;rsquo;ll show how you can do that too, even if I will keep using Netlify.
Why build with GitHub actions and not let Netlify do all the job? Well, there is definitely good reasons to let Netlify do all the work for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing your Blogdown Workflow</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</guid>
      <description>For more than a year now I have avoided updating my hugo-version on netlify and updating my theme because there was a lot of work that needed to be done to make that happen. I did not really have enough time or motivation to actually get it sorted, as it involved understanding theme changes and hugo changes.
But last week I finally got working on it, and decided I would not stop until I had it done.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
