<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The ggseg-suite</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/ggseg-suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/ggseg-suite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;R-Packages&lt;/strong&gt;: A set of packages for visualizing brain atlas data in R.
The packages create the possibility of visualizing brain atlas data directly in 2d fully inflated brains or brain slices through ggplot2, and as 3d mesh plots through plotly.
They are intended to create easier workflows for researchers working in R and neuroimaging, reducing the need to switch between software too often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggseg</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/ggseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/ggseg/</guid>
      <description>This package is developed with co-worker Didac Vidal Pineiro, whose had the whole idea.
This package is meant to use for visualizing brain segmentations, often referred to as brain atlases. Click the eye below to see a demonstration of the package.
It is also ready to install using devtools in R, directly from github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggseg3d</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/ggseg3d/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/ggseg3d/</guid>
      <description>This package is based on my initial idea, and developed with co-worker Didac Vidal Piñeiro.
This package is meant to use for visualizing brain segmentations, often referred to as brain atlases. Click the eye below to see a demonstration of the package.
It is also ready to install using devtools in R, directly from github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggsegExtra</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/ggsegextra/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/ggsegextra/</guid>
      <description>This package is an addon-package to the ggseg-suite of packages. It contains functions to create your own atlases compatible with the ggseg-packages, and includes a curated list of repositories with ggseg compatible atlases.
It is also ready to install using devtools in R, directly from github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nettskjemar</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/nettskjemar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/r-paks/nettskjemar/</guid>
      <description>This package uses the nettskjema API developed by the University of Oslo IT, making it possible to communicate with the University of Oslo specialized survey platform &amp;rsquo;nettskjema&amp;rsquo;. Currently the package is geared towards downloading and creating data.frames in R from answers to surveys. This is an easy and convenient way for people to access data they have stored in the survey platform into R and ready for analyses.
It is also ready to install using devtools in R, directly from github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating post summary with AI from Hugging Face</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/ai-blog-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/ai-blog-summary/</guid>
      <description>When you have lots of old blog posts, writing good summaries for SEO can be very tedious. Using AI, we can get summaries for our posts easily. Using httr2 we can access models through the Hugging Face API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making your blog FAIR</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/fair-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/fair-blog/</guid>
      <description>In August, Heidi Seibold wrote in her Newsletter about how she made it FAIR.
This made me think about my own writing and how to secure the content even when/if I port by blog or change its structure.
Here, I show how I use R, GitHub Actions and Zenodo API to create dois for all my posts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Positron IDE - A new IDE for data science</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/positron/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/positron/</guid>
      <description>In May I wrote about my favorite IDE&amp;rsquo;s.
As a result of that post, I was asked to join Posits private beta-testers for their new IDE, Positron.
Now Positron is out of private beta, so let&amp;rsquo;s see if it can replace my current favorite IDE&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving your GitHub Profile</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/github-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/github-profile/</guid>
      <description>GitHub is a major developer platform, and your profile is the first thing people see when they visit your account.
Your GitHub profile should then showcase who you are, what you know and what you&amp;rsquo;re learning.
This is how I vamped up my GitHub profile, to showcase who I am, what I know and what I&amp;rsquo;m learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customise your R startup message</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/rproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/rproject/</guid>
      <description>We all know the R startup message. It tells us the version
of R we are running, the date, the platform we are running
on, and some informative tips on using R.
When you&amp;rsquo;ve been using R a while, though, it gets old.
Let me show you how you can customise your startup message!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The IDEs I use</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/ide/</guid>
      <description>People who code have a tendency to spend a lot of time in various IDEs (Integrated Development Environments). They can be as simple as a text editor or as complex as a full-blown development environment. In this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through my two go-to IDE&amp;rsquo;s, RStudio and VScode, and why I switch between them rather than sticking to a single one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too much git cleaning</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/git-clean-woes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/git-clean-woes/</guid>
      <description>Version control is great, but sometimes it can trip you up!
In this post I recount my rather stupid mistake of using &lt;code&gt;git clean&lt;/code&gt; when I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have, and how I got out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Freesurfer LMM through R</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/freesurfer-lmm-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/freesurfer-lmm-r/</guid>
      <description>Running Freesurfer Linear Mixed Models on vertex-vise data is a
popular way of capturing more advanced statistical models in
neuroimaging. In this post I highlight how you can prepare your
data in R for Freesurfer LMMs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching you - teaching me</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/teaching-unlocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/teaching-unlocks/</guid>
      <description>Teaching can be extremely rewarding, and teaching can be rewarding . Teaching you - teaching me is the beauty of teaching . I love teaching coding and programming, and helping scientists unlock a new way of working . My university hosts an annual event called [Digital Scholarship Days] This year, I taught two workshops at the Universtity of Oslo .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo Igloo theme</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/hugo-igloo/</guid>
      <description>This is a theme for creating a website theme for the &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; static site generator. The Hugo Igloo
theme is the theme of my website and created using UIkit 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, New blog</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2024/newyear-newblog/</guid>
      <description>New year, a new blog, and some reflections on the past year that has passed . I&amp;rsquo;m taking the lead for a new Core Facility at the University of Oslo . I also got funding from my university to establish a Hub/Node network, which is an initiative from University IT to facilitate exchange of knowledhe between University staff .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reorganising Hugo Content and Aliasing</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/reorganising-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Hugo Aliasing is a stickler for good organisation of content . Reorganising Hugo Content and Aliasing has a nice way of dealing with that, which they call [gohugoioio] Reorganisation concept is that people should redirect to the specific page that they should be using .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Posit::conf 2023</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/positconf-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2023/positconf-2023/</guid>
      <description>There is a general air of excitement, nerdiness and support I just rarely feel at any other conf I go to. Posit::conf is like it gathers all the best Data science and R geeks in one place and we just go bananas in each others company. I&amp;rsquo;d like to share some thoughts and joys I had in the 4 days of the conf .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advent of R Functions</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2022/advent-of-r-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2022/advent-of-r-functions/</guid>
      <description>Advent of R Functions is a series of 24 pieces of code I often use in my work . This advent brings you 24 code examples that I hope can be of interest and help to you . I&amp;rsquo;ll continue using the calendar as for this first part of the first day of the month .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Get Apply&#39;ing</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2022/lets-get-applying/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2022/lets-get-applying/</guid>
      <description>When programming we want to write code that iterates well, we do this through loops . Let&amp;rsquo;s Get Apply&amp;rsquo;ing is based on the very well-known &lt;code&gt;mtcars&lt;/code&gt; dataset built-in to R . We&amp;rsquo;ll only use two columns, just to keep it simple .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R and the Tidyverse for working with data</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/tidyverse_carpentry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/tidyverse_carpentry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;: How to work efficiently with datasets in R using the Tidyverse, a Carpentries-style workshop.
The workshop is intended to be interactive, was initially developed to be run as a webinar, and can be expanded to single or two whole day workshop.
The workshop is intended both for R beginners as well as intermediate R users who know base-R well but wish to learn more about the Tidyverse way of working with data.
At the end of the workshop you will have a grasp of the Tidyverse way of working with data, and have learned new ways of efficiently working with data in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rmarkdown Child Templates</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/rmarkdown-child-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/rmarkdown-child-templates/</guid>
      <description>Rmarkdown has been working on a set of analyses from a survey at work . The survey has two basic type of questions, likert-scale questions and binary yes/no questions . For each of these two types of . questions, I’ve needed to generate a . set of descriptive plots and tables, as well as run a particular set of statistical models . I know how to make Rmark down parametrised reports, and I kind of wanted something similar, but in a nested fashion .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding giscus to your blogdown site</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/adding-giscus-to-your-blogdown-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/adding-giscus-to-your-blogdown-site/</guid>
      <description>Adding giscus to your blogdown site is an easy way to get your comment section working with blogdown/hugo . The following steps are outlined in the guide to getting it working with hugo and blogdown . The steps include creating a new layout file and setting up GitHub discissions .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GitHub Actions to Build your Hugo Website</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/using-github-actions-to-build-your-hugo-website/</guid>
      <description>Using GitHub Actions is a service that runs Continuous Integration, meaning that using a set-up file you can ask workers (computers run by GitHub) to do certain operations on your repository at certain triggers (at push, pull-requests or even on a schedule with crontab) This is where GitHub Actions shines. It is free and so are its actions for small jobs like what we want to do . To build on Netlify, you need all your content version controlled, in my case with git, and stored on GitHub . This is fine and dandy for text files like markdown, csv data, and images that &lt;em&gt;will not change often&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New {ggseg} with Geom!</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/new-ggseg-with-geom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2021/new-ggseg-with-geom/</guid>
      <description>A new version of ggseg R-package for visualisations of brain atlases was released a couple of months ago . I wanted to create such an update for a long time, but getting the internal logics of a ggplot geom working as I wanted was rather difficult . New {ggseg} with Geom! The position is what I&amp;rsquo;m truly happy about!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Wishes</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/new-year-s-wishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/new-year-s-wishes/</guid>
      <description>New Year&amp;rsquo;s Wishes is a ggplot2 holiday card wishing you all a better 2021 than 2020! I find these holiday cards help me understand and explore how data need to look to create a certain output . I wanted to use &lt;code&gt;ggforce::geom_circle&lt;/code&gt; for this, which would need x and y coordinates for the center of the circle and the radius .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R-Package Advent Calendar 2020</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/r-package-advent-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/r-package-advent-calendar/</guid>
      <description>The advent calendar is one R-package per day that I personally use and find very useful in my work . The hope is that it would give people a mix of familiar and less familiar packages that might help their work too . R-Package Advent Calendar 2020 is one package per day .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quartaki - Introduction to Quarto</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/quartaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/projects/quartaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;strong&gt;Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;: A 6 hour introduction to Quarto for report generation in R. Combining code with prose to create reports in a seamless environment. This workshop is taught with RStudio and R, but learners proficient in other compatible languages are welcome to join.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Linear Regression Family in R</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/the-linear-regression-family-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/the-linear-regression-family-in-r/</guid>
      <description>In this post we will go through examples of how we can specify different linear models (linear regressions) in R . The Linear Regression Family in RI will focus on how you can run models in R, and it will be up to you to try to translate your hypothesis into a model .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing your Blogdown Workflow</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/changing-you-blogdown-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Blogdown is usually used with [go hugo], a static webpage builder . Blogdown renders directly from &lt;code&gt;Rmd&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;html, meaning it circumvents hugo&#39;s processing of &lt;/code&gt;md` . This can cause some unwanted issues depending on your theme . It can also make it difficult to maintain your webpage over time .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Freesurfer annotation files to plot in R</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/using-freesurfer-annotation-files-to-plot-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/using-freesurfer-annotation-files-to-plot-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Using Freesurfer, the Desikan Killany coortical atlas (aparc) is an atlas that consist of 36 segments, which are well-defined &lt;a href=&#34;https://surfer.mgh.harvard.edu/fswiki/CorticalParcellation?action=AttachFile&amp;amp;do=get&amp;amp;target=annot-desikan-m.jpg&#34;&gt;Automatically Parcellating the Human Cerebral Cortex&lt;/a&gt; Using Freisurfer annotation files to plot in R is our package where you can render the proper 3d version using ggplot2 .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you wanna build a snowman?</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/do-you-wanna-build-a-snowman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/do-you-wanna-build-a-snowman/</guid>
      <description>Do you wanna build a snowman? Do you want to build a Christmas tree? We&amp;rsquo;re going to use [ggforce] from the [gg force] package by Thomas Lin Pedersen . We need to specify the center of the circles we&amp;rsquo;re drawing&amp;rsquo;s locations and their radii . We use &amp;lsquo;geom_circle&amp;rsquo; and &amp;rsquo;tidyr&amp;rsquo; to create the snowman .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggseg3d - creating interactive brain segmentation plots with plotly</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/ggseg3d-creating-interactive-brain-segmentation-plots-with-plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/ggseg3d-creating-interactive-brain-segmentation-plots-with-plotly/</guid>
      <description>ggseg3d is a package for 3d mesh plots of brain atlases using plotly . It is made to plot brain atlas data . It should be fairly easy to use or atlele to make the first plot . It can be installed from our works GitHub account using remotes .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting GAMM interactions with ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Plotting GAMM interactions with ggplot2 is not always easy, especially if you have some interactions in there . Plotting the results of GAMMs are not always so easy . I&amp;rsquo;ll be using the &lt;code&gt;diamonds&lt;/code&gt; dataset for this, as it has some nice non-linear features .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Psychologists - part II</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/r-for-psychologists-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/r-for-psychologists-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>R for Psychologists - part III: Getting SPSS data into R, doing some data wrangling (altering the data), plotting, and running a simple linear model . Part II: Plotting in R through &lt;code&gt;ggplot2&lt;/code&gt; really is a way to understand how to organise and alter data in R to suit your needs .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building tidy tools - a quick recap of RStudio::conf 2019 workshop &amp; teeny demonstration</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/building-tidy-tools-a-quick-recap-of-rstudio-conf-2019-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/building-tidy-tools-a-quick-recap-of-rstudio-conf-2019-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Building tidy tools - a quick recap of RStudio::conf 2019 workshop &amp;amp; teeny demonstration . I attended a two-day workshop with Charlotte Wickham and Hadley Wickham . The sibling duo of R-package development did not fail to deliver what the workshop title announced, a workshop in how to create packages in a tidy way .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why RStudio::conf is the best conference experience I have had</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/why-rstudio-conf-is-the-best-conference-experience-i-have-had/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/why-rstudio-conf-is-the-best-conference-experience-i-have-had/</guid>
      <description>RStudio::conf Austin is the best conference experience I have had . It was thoroughly enjoyable and educational to see the different ways the same tools were applied to solve &amp;ldquo;real life-life problems&amp;rdquo; It was also enjoyable to see how they applied to problems in industry to solve real life problems . It is the empitamy of what this community actually is .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas tree in ggplot</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/christmas-tree-in-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/christmas-tree-in-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Rladies.org showed me this cool thing a stats professor does each Christmas at the end of his visualisation lecture, I knew I had to do it! You can see all the lovely submissions he has &lt;a href=&#34;http://smarterpoland.pl/index.php/2017/12/christmas-trees/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for psychologists - just dive into it!</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/r-just-dive-into-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/r-just-dive-into-it/</guid>
      <description>R requires you to be proficient in R in a different way than SPSS . Once you are proficient enough in R, you have a gazillion tools to do more or less anything you want to do, be it analysing complex data, a simple linear regression, writing a blog or making interactive data portals . RStudio is a completely blank slate, no data, no fancy stuff, just a program .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the brain animated!</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/get-the-brain-animated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/get-the-brain-animated/</guid>
      <description>The ggseg package was so well received that we almost immediately got it on [Neuroconductor]. We got some pull requests from people helping us improve the code, and particularly get it ready for CRAN when we decide to submit it there . The package vignettes are update on how you may supply data for facetting .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the ggseg R-package for brain segmentations</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</guid>
      <description>The ggseg R-package for brain segmentations is intended for those who need to easily plot results or overviews of segmentet data . The package is developed as part of our lab [The Center for Lifespanism and Cognition [LCBC-UiO]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular plots in R and adding images</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</guid>
      <description>Circular plots are becoming more and more popular in for visualising associatetions between different phenomena . I think they look pretty cool, and while I have not yet published a paper with it, I did prep a lot of scripts for plotting my analysis results with it .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding external images to plots</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/adding-external-images-to-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/adding-external-images-to-plots/</guid>
      <description>Adding external images to plots is a good way to showcase results, and make it easier for me and my reader to understand what the findings are . I use [ImageMagick] for this, but there are R-packages to help, like [imager] and [imaging] software .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working a lot with Generalized Additive Mixed Mixed Models (GAMMs) I started seeing some differences in the output from other mixed models I had run through [lme4] and even Bayesian mixed models with [rstanarm] The random effects terms were specified differently . At first I thought this was mainly the fact that I was now using smoothing splines, which I was unfamiliar with running before .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>A co-worker was working on some generalized additive mixed models (GAMM) through the R package [mgcv] The analyses work very well, and results were as expected . There were also some built in plotting functions for the gamm output in R . However, they were with base-r, and we all know base r is not the most beautiful .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/about/resume/am_mowinckel_cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/about/resume/am_mowinckel_cv/</guid>
      <description>Education # A tibble: 3 × 5 what when with where why &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;glu&amp;gt; &amp;lt;glu&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;lis&amp;gt; 1 Thesis title: Neurocognitive Processes of Decision-ma… 2012… Phil… &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; 2 Thesis title: Default Mode Resting-State Functional C… 2009… Mast… &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; 3 Thesis title: Attention Deficits in Mild Cognitive Im… 2006… Bach… &amp;lt;NA&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; Research positions # A tibble: 3 × 5 what when with where why &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;glue&amp;gt; &amp;lt;glue&amp;gt; &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;lis&amp;gt; 1 Staff scientist 2018 - present University o… Oslo &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; 2 Researcher / Project Manager 2016 - 2017 University o… Oslo &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; 3 Research assistant and lab-technician 2011 - 2012 University o… Oslo &amp;lt;chr&amp;gt; Memberships &amp;amp; Services I am passionate about increasing the representation and retention of women in science, and in improving the formal training and competencies taught at the University.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
