<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Circluar plots in R and adding images</title>
      <link>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</guid>
      <description>Last post was definately my most succesful (and I have so much experience :P). But it was fun with all the feedback and appreciation. So I’ll continue with a little more plotting. Cirlular plots are becoming more and more popular in for visualising associatetions between different phenomena. I think they look pretty cool, and while I have not yet published a paper with it, I did prep a lot of scripts for plotting my analysis results with it, with BRAINS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding external images to plots</title>
      <link>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago we had out first RLadies-Oslo meetup! It was such a great turnout, and I had so much fun presenting to the group of lovely folks!
First @RLadies_Oslo meetup with @DrMowinckels: &amp;quot;I love plotting&amp;quot; ♥️ #rstats #Rladies pic.twitter.com/UTS5QCy3HE
&amp;mdash; Lene Drøsdal (@ldrosdal) April 23, 2018  And indeed it is true, I love plotting. Probably more than I love analysing data (and definately more than cleaning and wrangling :P).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>I’m working a lot with Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) lately, and so, it seems I will be doing a small series on them as we go now. After a little feedback, I did some small alterations to the last post, hopefully it is a little easier to follow, you can read it here.
For this part I’d like to talk about random effects in mgcv::gamm as they are a little different from what I am used to from, for instance lme4 or even a standard GAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Here we go! Stepping into the world of blogging through R and blogdown! This is both super exciting and slightly scary, I have not really shared code online like I plan here before. But I guess we start somewhere. And we start with plotting.
A co-worker was working on some generalized additive mixed models (GAMM) through the R package mgcv. The analyses work very well, and results were as expected. There were also some built in plotting functions for the gamm output in R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>