<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Longcovid on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/tags/longcovid/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Longcovid on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 01:22:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/tags/longcovid/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unmasking Long Covid: PCA &amp; Clustering Analysis of Symptom Syndromes</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2025/visible-pca/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2025/visible-pca/</guid>
      <description>This blog post delves into the my personal Long Covid data, collected via the Visible app, using Principal Component Analysis (PCA). I detail four key clusters: Menstruation, Exertion, Emotional, and Neurological and then compare these clusters to the principal components derived from PCA. The analysis aims to provide a validated, data-driven framework for exploring my symptoms during this condition, using clear visualisations to showcase the results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A year with Visible Long-Covid Tracking</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2025/visible/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2025/visible/</guid>
      <description>This post dives into a year of tracking Long Covid symptoms and progress using the Visible app. Dr. Mowinckel, a quantitative scientist, shares their experience monitoring heart rate, heart rate variability (HRV), daily symptoms, and functional capacity using the app&amp;rsquo;s features and the FUNCAP27 questionnaire. Discover how this data provides insights into pacing strategies, identifies potential warning signs like HRV spikes, and reveals meaningful clusters of interconnected symptoms and experiences. Explore the journey of living with and managing Long Covid through the lens of personal health data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The difficult year</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2025/the-difficult-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2025/the-difficult-year/</guid>
      <description>A deeply personal reflection on a challenging year with long COVID, highlighting the journey through illness, rehab, support from loved ones, and small victories. Despite physical limitations, resilience shines through monthly blog updates, a newsletter, and plans for gradual recovery in the coming year.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
