<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Plots on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/tags/plots/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Plots on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 01:15:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/tags/plots/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Year&#39;s Wishes</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/new-year-s-wishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/new-year-s-wishes/</guid>
      <description>Here&amp;rsquo;s a ggplot2 holiday card wishing you a better 2021! Explore how to create a festive holiday plot in R with ggplot2. Understanding the preparation of data for plotting, using &lt;code&gt;geom_circle&lt;/code&gt;, adding blur effects, and customizing text. This exercise enhances your skills in working with ggplot2 and thinking critically about data structures and visual outputs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Freesurfer annotation files to plot in R</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/using-freesurfer-annotation-files-to-plot-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2020/using-freesurfer-annotation-files-to-plot-in-r/</guid>
      <description>For neuroimaging, toggling between R and imaging software like FSL or Freesurfer is common. We segment large 3D brain data into meaningful regions. Our ggseg and ggseg3d packages visualize the brain&amp;rsquo;s Desikan-Killany atlas in 2D and 3D. Learn the steps to convert Freesurfer annotation files to mesh files using the ggsegExtra package for enhanced brain data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Do you wanna build a snowman?</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/do-you-wanna-build-a-snowman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/do-you-wanna-build-a-snowman/</guid>
      <description>Celebrate with another Christmas special! Following last year&amp;rsquo;s festive ggplot tree, build an interactive snowman using R, ggplot2, ggforce, and gganimate. Learn to create a snowman from circles, add features like a face, arms, and accessories, and animate falling snow. Enhance your R skills and holiday spirit with this detailed tutorial, ending with a personalized &amp;ldquo;Merry Christmas!&amp;rdquo; message.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ggseg3d - creating interactive brain segmentation plots with plotly</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/ggseg3d-creating-interactive-brain-segmentation-plots-with-plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/ggseg3d-creating-interactive-brain-segmentation-plots-with-plotly/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to create interactive 3D brain atlas plots using the ggseg3d package in R. Learn to visualize neuroimaging data with plotly, including setting up and customizing brain atlas plots. Ideal for neuroscientists and data scientists working with brain segmentation data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the ggseg R-package for brain segmentations</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</guid>
      <description>Discover ggseg, an R package designed for plotting brain segmentations directly in R with ggplot2. Learn how to visualize results from different brain atlases, customize plots, and integrate your own data. Ideal for neuroimaging researchers needing to plot segmented brain data efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circular plots in R and adding images</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last post was definately my most succesful (and I have so much experience :P). But it was fun with all the feedback and appreciation. So I&amp;rsquo;ll continue with a little more plotting. Circular plots are becoming more and more popular in for visualising associatetions between different phenomena. I think they look pretty cool, and while I have not yet published a paper with it, I did prep a lot of scripts for plotting my analysis results with it, with BRAINS! because, brains make it better. Always.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
