<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 12:21:16 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ggseg</title>
      <link>/projects/ggseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ggseg/</guid>
      <description>This package is developed with co-worker Didac Vidal Pineiro, whose had the whole idea.
This package is meant to use for visualizing brain segmentations, often referred to as brain atlases. There is currenlty no shiny demonstration of it, but we will make that at some point.
It is, however, ready to install using devtools in R, directly from github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI viewer</title>
      <link>/projects/rmriviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/rmriviewer/</guid>
      <description>There is currently a lack of tools for vislualising results from MRI analyses in R, most packages call an external command to open a viewer in another program. There is, however, advantages to visualise directly from R, among other increased understanding of the underlying data.
In this project, tentatively called visMRI, the idea is to create a shiny instance that will function as a viewer for MRI results. Ultimately, I hope to launch something that might be used on a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the ggseg R-package for brain segmentations</title>
      <link>/blog/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Though posted only a week ago, we have discovered another R package called ggBrain which has slightly different functions than what our package has. Because of this, we have altered the name of our package to ggseg short for ggsegmentation which is a better description of what our package does.
I’ve not written a post in a while. Mostly because of summer vacation, and also because I have been a little swamped at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular plots in R and adding images</title>
      <link>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</guid>
      <description>Last post was definately my most succesful (and I have so much experience :P). But it was fun with all the feedback and appreciation. So I’ll continue with a little more plotting. Circular plots are becoming more and more popular in for visualising associatetions between different phenomena. I think they look pretty cool, and while I have not yet published a paper with it, I did prep a lot of scripts for plotting my analysis results with it, with BRAINS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding external images to plots</title>
      <link>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago we had out first RLadies-Oslo meetup! It was such a great turnout, and I had so much fun presenting to the group of lovely folks!
First @RLadies_Oslo meetup with @DrMowinckels: &amp;quot;I love plotting&amp;quot; ♥️ #rstats #Rladies pic.twitter.com/UTS5QCy3HE
&amp;mdash; Lene Drøsdal (@ldrosdal) April 23, 2018  And indeed it is true, I love plotting. Probably more than I love analysing data (and definately more than cleaning and wrangling :P).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>I’m working a lot with Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) lately, and so, it seems I will be doing a small series on them as we go now. After a little feedback, I did some small alterations to the last post, hopefully it is a little easier to follow, you can read it here.
For this part I’d like to talk about random effects in mgcv::gamm as they are a little different from what I am used to from, for instance lme4 or even a standard GAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Here we go! Stepping into the world of blogging through R and blogdown! This is both super exciting and slightly scary, I have not really shared code online like I plan here before. But I guess we start somewhere. And we start with plotting.
A co-worker was working on some generalized additive mixed models (GAMM) through the R package mgcv. The analyses work very well, and results were as expected. There were also some built in plotting functions for the gamm output in R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/aboutme/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutme/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>In short I am a cognitive neuroscientist based in Oslo, Norway, and works at the Center for Lifespan Changes in Brain and Cognition. I’m passionate about cognitive neuroscience, using R and teaching the world the wonders of R. Doing all I can to improve gender diversity in the R-community though RLadies-Oslo.
 Education    Start End Place Degree Field Thesis Grade    2017 2017 University of Oslo PhD Cognitive Neuroscience Neurocognitive Processes of Decision-making in Adults with ADHD   2009 2011 University of Oslo MPhil Cognitive Neuroscience Default Mode Resting-State Functional Connectivity of the Aging Brain B  2005 2009 University of Oslo BA Psychology Attention Deficits in Mild Cognitive Impairment and Dementia of the Alzheimer Type A     Work     Start End Place Position Responsibilities    2018 Current University of Oslo, LCBC Staff researcher Data-management in LCBC and the Lifebran EU-project  2016 2018 University of Oslo, LCBC Researcher/Project manager Co-ordinating data collection, data-management, and research collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a cognitive neuroscientist based in Oslo, Norway, who works at the Center for Lifespan Changes in Brain and Cognition. I am passionate about cognitive neuroscience, teaching people the benefits of using R, and equalizing gender diversity in the R-community (and in data science) through RLadies-Oslo.
More about me </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cookies/cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cookies/cookies/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>