<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:28 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ggseg</title>
      <link>/projects/ggseg/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/ggseg/</guid>
      <description>This package is developed with co-worker Didac Vidal Pineiro, whose had the whole idea.
This package is meant to use for visualizing brain segmentations, often referred to as brain atlases. Click the eye below to see a demonstration of the package.
It is also ready to install using devtools in R, directly from github.
&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;https://github.com/LCBC-UiO/ggseg&amp;rdquo; title=Github repository&amp;quot;&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI viewer</title>
      <link>/projects/rmriviewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 12:21:16 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/rmriviewer/</guid>
      <description>There is currently a lack of tools for visualising results from MRI analyses in R, most packages call an external command to open a viewer in another program. There is, however, advantages to visualise directly from R, among other increased understanding of the underlying data.
In this project, tentatively called visMRI, the idea is to create a shiny instance that will function as a viewer for MRI results. Ultimately, I hope to launch something that might be used on a .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photography</title>
      <link>/projects/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/photography/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes I take pictures This project is about the pictures I take. Sometimes, they are pictures of cats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design</title>
      <link>/projects/design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/design/</guid>
      <description>This theme was designed by Victoria Drake. Go on, explore! 💪
If you want to use it for your website, check out the section at the bottom of the main page. 👍</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing</title>
      <link>/projects/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/writing/</guid>
      <description>Aromatic aroma con panna, crema so coffee robust coffee barista, café au lait trifecta that strong blue mountain cortado aftertaste. Aroma extraction french press, skinny sweet, blue mountain cup roast barista, beans, extra cappuccino mug crema strong.
To go viennese cream to go, flavour, so mocha as, carajillo iced et a siphon froth. Aged, eu, cup, brewed aroma kopi-luwak, coffee, id viennese french press brewed grounds acerbic froth. Decaffeinated acerbic, spoon beans seasonal, french press café au lait mazagran roast chicory, pumpkin spice galão as fair trade, dark irish cup ristretto half and half whipped shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/aboutme/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/aboutme/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>In short I am a cognitive neuroscientist based in Oslo, Norway, and works at the Center for Lifespan Changes in Brain and Cognition. I’m passionate about cognitive neuroscience, using R and teaching the world the wonders of R. Doing all I can to improve gender diversity in the R-community though RLadies-Oslo.
 Education     Start End Place Degree Field Thesis Grade    2012 2017 University of Oslo PhD Cognitive Neuroscience Neurocognitive Processes of Decision-making in Adults with ADHD   2009 2011 University of Oslo MPhil Cognitive Neuroscience Default Mode Resting-State Functional Connectivity of the Aging Brain B  2005 2009 University of Oslo BA Psychology Attention Deficits in Mild Cognitive Impairment and Dementia of the Alzheimer Type A     Work     Start End Place Position Responsibilities    2018 Current University of Oslo, LCBC Staff scientist Data-management in LCBC and the Lifebrain EU-project  2016 2018 University of Oslo, LCBC Researcher/Project manager Co-ordinating data collection, data-management, and research collaborations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Freesurfer annotation files to plot in R</title>
      <link>/blog/using-freesurfer-annotation-files-to-plot-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/using-freesurfer-annotation-files-to-plot-in-r/</guid>
      <description>When you work with neuroimaging data like I do, you often find your self swapping back and forth between R and the imaging software of your choise. For me, that is usually FSL or Freesurfer. Since the resolution of the brain we have is quite large and 3 dimensional, we often reduce the data to segments that meaningfully go together. For instance, areas of the brain that control language or visual processing, or areas of the brain with similar structural properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do you wanna build a snowman?</title>
      <link>/blog/do-you-wanna-build-a-snowman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/do-you-wanna-build-a-snowman/</guid>
      <description>It’s time for another Christmas special. Last year I made a Christmas tree ggplot, and animated some snow and sparkling baubles. That was a lot of fun, and I decided I wanted to do something similar this year too. But this year we’re going to build a snowman.
Body A snowman needs a body, so lets start with that! Let’s go for a two large body ball’s, and a head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggseg3d - creating interactive brain segmentation plots with plotly</title>
      <link>/blog/ggseg3d-creating-interactive-brain-segmentation-plots-with-plotly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ggseg3d-creating-interactive-brain-segmentation-plots-with-plotly/</guid>
      <description>Looking through my blogposts, I realised I’ve never written about my colleague Didac and my package for 3d mesh plots of brain atlases using plotly. I’ve already showed some functionality from out {ggseg}-package, in the introductory blogpost and follow-up on animating it.
I guess it’s extra timely to do it now, as we recently split the mesh-plot function off the main {ggseg}-package and into it’s own package, and also did some re-writing of core-functionality of the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting GAMM interactions with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>I’m full of making packages and unit testing these days, and I don’t feel particularly confident in my unit testing skills to be sharing those yet. But, thankfully, I am also back in the GAMM corner lately. There is something very satisfying to me about running appropriate models and seeing the results. But, plotting the results of GAMMs are not always so easy, especially if you have some interactions in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Psychologists - part II</title>
      <link>/blog/r-for-psychologists-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-for-psychologists-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a very long time since I wrote anything. Life has been unexpectedly overwhelming for a period, still is I guess, but one musters on. I’m sitting in old town Fredrikstad while my cat is getting some tests at the vets’, so I finally get some time and want to write something here. And we will continue with some R for Psychologists.
I my first R for Psychologists post we really dove into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building tidy tools - a quick recap of RStudio::conf 2019 workshop &amp; teeny demonstration</title>
      <link>/blog/building-tidy-tools-a-quick-recap-of-rstudio-conf-2019-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/building-tidy-tools-a-quick-recap-of-rstudio-conf-2019-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I’ve already posted about what I liked so much about RStudio::conf 2019, and while I could continue chanting that over and over without it ever being able to properly convey how lovely it was, I am going to continue into another report from the conference.
There were several pre-conference workshops to attend, which I of course signed up for. After debating heavily with my self of what to choose, the cruelty was really that all the workshops looked amazing, I decided to go for “Building tidy tools” with Charlotte Wickham and Hadley Wickham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why RStudio::conf is the best conference experience I have had</title>
      <link>/blog/why-rstudio-conf-is-the-best-conference-experience-i-have-had/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-rstudio-conf-is-the-best-conference-experience-i-have-had/</guid>
      <description>There is something to be said about the R-community. Actually, there is a lot to be said about the R-community, and I believe RStudio::conf is the empitamy of what this community actually is. While I’m in my hotel room as RStudio::conf Austin has just wrapped up, ending with an amazing Birds of a Feather session with RLadies, I’m having so many thoughts and feelings about this experience. I’m on a complete high, and cannot fathom that I just participated in something like this conference, which is quite something different than any other conference I have been to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas tree in ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/christmas-tree-in-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/christmas-tree-in-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>It’s Christmas! And I love Christmas! Pretty snow, cozy fires, fairy lights, family, friends and love. It’s just filled with all times of lovely things.
That also means… PLOTS! You might know from my previous posts that I love plotting. A bit too much, but it truly is a lovely thing to create a great plot.
So, a while ago, the amazing RLadies network showed me this cool thing a stats professor does each Christmas at the end of his visualisation lecture, I knew I had to do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for psychologists - just dive into it!</title>
      <link>/blog/r-just-dive-into-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-just-dive-into-it/</guid>
      <description>I recently was talking with a good friend and brilliant researcher regarding the advantages of R. As you can guess, I was the advocate. Coming from psychology, we are mainly taught to use “simple” analysis tools, and mainly SPSS. I never liked SPSS, even as a student. not knowing of any possible alternatives or what could be improved, I just thought the whole thing felt too black-boxy. But it is a convenient tool, when the data is already in a relatively clean format, and the analyses you want to do are straight forward, and you don’t mind not knowing exactly the formula SPSS uses to calculate your results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the brain animated!</title>
      <link>/blog/get-the-brain-animated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/get-the-brain-animated/</guid>
      <description>I’m super delighted that our ggseg package was so well received! We almost immediately got it on Neuroconductor, which is a neuroimaging equivalent to Bioconductor. We got some pull requests from people helping us improve the code, and particularly get it ready for CRAN when we decide to submit it there.
In all of this, I learned so much about creating packages, and ended up making quite a major alteration to the base-functions of the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the ggseg R-package for brain segmentations</title>
      <link>/blog/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Though posted only a week ago, we have discovered another R package called ggBrain which has slightly different functions than what our package has. Because of this, we have altered the name of our package to ggseg short for ggsegmentation which is a better description of what our package does.
I’ve not written a post in a while. Mostly because of summer vacation, and also because I have been a little swamped at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular plots in R and adding images</title>
      <link>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</guid>
      <description>Last post was definately my most succesful (and I have so much experience :P). But it was fun with all the feedback and appreciation. So I’ll continue with a little more plotting. Circular plots are becoming more and more popular in for visualising associatetions between different phenomena. I think they look pretty cool, and while I have not yet published a paper with it, I did prep a lot of scripts for plotting my analysis results with it, with BRAINS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding external images to plots</title>
      <link>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago we had out first RLadies-Oslo meetup! It was such a great turnout, and I had so much fun presenting to the group of lovely folks!
First @RLadies_Oslo meetup with @DrMowinckels: &amp;quot;I love plotting&amp;quot; ♥️ #rstats #Rladies pic.twitter.com/UTS5QCy3HE
&amp;mdash; Lene Drøsdal (@ldrosdal) April 23, 2018  And indeed it is true, I love plotting. Probably more than I love analysing data (and definately more than cleaning and wrangling :P).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>I’m working a lot with Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) lately, and so, it seems I will be doing a small series on them as we go now. After a little feedback, I did some small alterations to the last post, hopefully it is a little easier to follow, you can read it here.
For this part I’d like to talk about random effects in mgcv::gamm as they are a little different from what I am used to from, for instance lme4 or even a standard GAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Here we go! Stepping into the world of blogging through R and blogdown! This is both super exciting and slightly scary, I have not really shared code online like I plan here before. But I guess we start somewhere. And we start with plotting.
A co-worker was working on some generalized additive mixed models (GAMM) through the R package mgcv. The analyses work very well, and results were as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:23:28 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 13:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I am a cognitive neuroscientist based in Oslo, Norway, who works at the Center for Lifespan Changes in Brain and Cognition. I am passionate about cognitive neuroscience, teaching people the benefits of using R, and improving gender diversity and equity in the R-community (and in data science) through RLadies-Oslo. More about me&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/cookies/cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cookies/cookies/</guid>
      <description>  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>