<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Talks &amp; Workshops on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Talks &amp; Workshops on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>**Talks**: The ggseg-suite of R-packages</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/talks-ggseg-suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/talks-ggseg-suite/</guid>
      <description>This is a lit of talks I have had for the ggseg-suite of package developed by myself and my co-worker Didac Vidal-Piñeiro.
The packages create the possibility of visualizing brain atlas data directly in 2d fully inflated brains or brain slices through ggplot2, and as 3d mesh plots through plotly. They are intended to create easier workflows for researchers working in R and neuroimaging, reducing the need to switch between software too often.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Talks:** Oslo Psychscience</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/video-oslo-psychscience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/video-oslo-psychscience/</guid>
      <description>We started Oslo Psychscience as a science communication challenge for young researchers at the Department of Psychology, at the University of Oslo. Guro Løseth Engvik and I arranged Pecha Kucha nights with young researchers presenting their projects. I have presented here twice, and been the host of one.
Recordings 01.05.2019 - Healthy minds from 0-100 years: Optimising the use of European brain imaging cohorts
15.12.2014 - Why study ADHD?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Talks:** R-Ladies</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/talks-rladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/talks-rladies/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had R-Ladies talks both locally to the local Oslo chapter, the Norwegian Bergen chapter and also for R-Ladies London. I try reaching out to local R-Ladies chapters when I travel and offer a talk. It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to meet new people and get inspiration from other chapters!
Talks 06.10.2020 - Bergen / Online - Workshop: Linear mixed models in R 11.05.2020 - Oslo - Reports to impress your boss  30.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Workshop:** Introduction to Linear Mixed Models in R</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/workshops-lmm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/workshops-lmm/</guid>
      <description>This is a 2 hour workshop in doing Linear Mixed Models in R. The workshop is intended to be interactive, and can be expanded to a whole day.
This workshop is an introductory workshop in Linear Mixed Models in R.
It will cover some basic information on how to identify if a data-set is ill-suited for standard linear models, and mixed models are better.
After this it covers how to specify linear mixed models, inspect the model output, and create tables and figures based on the model results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>**Workshop:** Tidyverse Quick Introduction</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/workshops-tidyquintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/workshops/workshops-tidyquintro/</guid>
      <description>This is a 4 hour workshop on working with the tidyverse packages in R. The workshop is intended to be interactive, was initially developed to be run as a webinar, and can be expanded to single or two whole day workshop.
R has become a popular tool for doing statistical analysis. However, the sheer number of different packages for data preparation and analysis makes R code heterogeneous, hard to read, and error-prone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
