<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GAMM on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>https://drmowinckels.io/tags/gamm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GAMM on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 11:23:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drmowinckels.io/tags/gamm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plotting GAMM interactions with ggplot2</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2019/plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to visualize Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) with interactions in R using ggplot2 and mgcv. This tutorial covers numeric and factor interactions, creating prediction datasets, and generating smooth plots. Ideal for enhancing your data analysis and visualization skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>Explore the use of Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) with random effects using &lt;code&gt;mgcv&lt;/code&gt; in R. This blog post covers the differences between specifying random effects in &lt;code&gt;mgcv&lt;/code&gt; compared to other packages like &lt;code&gt;lme4&lt;/code&gt; and walks through a detailed example with simulated data. Learn about &lt;code&gt;gamm&lt;/code&gt; model output, interpreting random effects, and plot comparisons of different model specifications.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drmowinckels.io/blog/2018/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Discover how to plot Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) using ggplot2 in R. This tutorial covers generating simulated data, creating GAMM models with mgcv, predicting single predictor effects, and using the itsadug package for smooth predictions. Learn the steps to visualize complex models and create informative plots.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
