<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting GAMM results with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/plotting-gamm-results-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/plotting-gamm-results-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>I’m full of making packages and unit testing these days, and I don’t feel particularly confident in my unit testing skills to be sharing those yet. But, thankfully, I am also back in the GAMM corner lately. There is something very satisfying to me about running appropriate models and seeing the results. But, plotting the results of GAMMs are not always so easy, especially if you have some interactions in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for Psychologists - part II</title>
      <link>/blog/r-for-psychologists-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-for-psychologists-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>It’s been a very long time since I wrote anything. Life has been unexpectedly overwhelming for a period, still is I guess, but one musters on. I’m sitting in old town Fredrikstad while my cat is getting some tests at the vets’, so I finally get some time and want to write something here. And we will continue with some R for Psychologists.
I my first R for Psychologists post we really dove into it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building tidy tools - a quick recap of RStudio::conf 2019 workshop &amp; teeny demonstration</title>
      <link>/blog/building-tidy-tools-a-quick-recap-of-rstudio-conf-2019-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/building-tidy-tools-a-quick-recap-of-rstudio-conf-2019-workshop/</guid>
      <description>I’ve already posted about what I liked so much about RStudio::conf 2019, and while I could continue chanting that over and over without it ever being able to properly convey how lovely it was, I am going to continue into another report from the conference.
There were several pre-conference workshops to attend, which I of course signed up for. After debating heavily with my self of what to choose, the cruelty was really that all the workshops looked amazing, I decided to go for “Building tidy tools” with Charlotte Wickham and Hadley Wickham.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why RStudio::conf is the best conference experience I have had</title>
      <link>/blog/why-rstudio-conf-is-the-best-conference-experience-i-have-had/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/why-rstudio-conf-is-the-best-conference-experience-i-have-had/</guid>
      <description>There is something to be said about the R-community. Actually, there is a lot to be said about the R-community, and I believe RStudio::conf is the empitamy of what this community actually is. While I’m in my hotel room as RStudio::conf Austin has just wrapped up, ending with an amazing Birds of a Feather session with RLadies, I’m having so many thoughts and feelings about this experience. I’m on a complete high, and cannot fathom that I just participated in something like this conference, which is quite something different than any other conference I have been to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas tree in ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/christmas-tree-in-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/christmas-tree-in-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>It’s Christmas! And I love Christmas! Pretty snow, cozy fires, fairy lights, family, friends and love. It’s just filled with all times of lovely things.
That also means… PLOTS! You might know from my previous posts that I love plotting. A bit too much, but it truly is a lovely thing to create a great plot.
So, a while ago, the amazing RLadies network showed me this cool thing a stats professor does each Christmas at the end of his visualisation lecture, I knew I had to do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R for psychologists - just dive into it!</title>
      <link>/blog/r-just-dive-into-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/r-just-dive-into-it/</guid>
      <description>I recently was talking with a good friend and brilliant researcher regarding the advantages of R. As you can guess, I was the advocate. Coming from psychology, we are mainly taught to use “simple” analysis tools, and mainly SPSS. I never liked SPSS, even as a student. not knowing of any possible alternatives or what could be improved, I just thought the whole thing felt too black-boxy. But it is a convenient tool, when the data is already in a relatively clean format, and the analyses you want to do are straight forward, and you don’t mind not knowing exactly the formula SPSS uses to calculate your results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get the brain animated!</title>
      <link>/blog/get-the-brain-animated/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/get-the-brain-animated/</guid>
      <description>I’m super delighted that our ggseg package was so well received! We almost immediately got it on Neuroconductor, which is a neuroimaging equivalent to Bioconductor. We got some pull requests from people helping us improve the code, and particularly get it ready for CRAN when we decide to submit it there.
In all of this, I learned so much about creating packages, and ended up making quite a major alteration to the base-functions of the package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing the ggseg R-package for brain segmentations</title>
      <link>/blog/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/introducing-the-ggseg-r-package-for-brain-segmentations/</guid>
      <description>Edit: Though posted only a week ago, we have discovered another R package called ggBrain which has slightly different functions than what our package has. Because of this, we have altered the name of our package to ggseg short for ggsegmentation which is a better description of what our package does.
I’ve not written a post in a while. Mostly because of summer vacation, and also because I have been a little swamped at work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circular plots in R and adding images</title>
      <link>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/circluar-plots-in-r-and-adding-images/</guid>
      <description>Last post was definately my most succesful (and I have so much experience :P). But it was fun with all the feedback and appreciation. So I’ll continue with a little more plotting. Circular plots are becoming more and more popular in for visualising associatetions between different phenomena. I think they look pretty cool, and while I have not yet published a paper with it, I did prep a lot of scripts for plotting my analysis results with it, with BRAINS!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding external images to plots</title>
      <link>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/adding-external-images-to-plots/</guid>
      <description>Two weeks ago we had out first RLadies-Oslo meetup! It was such a great turnout, and I had so much fun presenting to the group of lovely folks!
First @RLadies_Oslo meetup with @DrMowinckels: &amp;quot;I love plotting&amp;quot; ♥️ #rstats #Rladies pic.twitter.com/UTS5QCy3HE
&amp;mdash; Lene Drøsdal (@ldrosdal) April 23, 2018  And indeed it is true, I love plotting. Probably more than I love analysing data (and definately more than cleaning and wrangling :P).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>I’m working a lot with Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) lately, and so, it seems I will be doing a small series on them as we go now. After a little feedback, I did some small alterations to the last post, hopefully it is a little easier to follow, you can read it here.
For this part I’d like to talk about random effects in mgcv::gamm as they are a little different from what I am used to from, for instance lme4 or even a standard GAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Here we go! Stepping into the world of blogging through R and blogdown! This is both super exciting and slightly scary, I have not really shared code online like I plan here before. But I guess we start somewhere. And we start with plotting.
A co-worker was working on some generalized additive mixed models (GAMM) through the R package mgcv. The analyses work very well, and results were as expected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>