<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GAMM on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</title>
    <link>/tags/gamm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GAMM on Dr. Mowinckel&#39;s</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gamm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting GAMM interactions with ggplot2</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-11-16-plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-11-16-plotting-gamm-interactions-with-ggplot2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m full of making packages and unit testing these days, and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel particularly confident in my unit testing skills to be sharing those yet. But, thankfully, I am also back in the GAMM corner lately. There is something very satisfying to me about running appropriate models and seeing the results. But, plotting the results of GAMMs are not always so easy, especially if you have some interactions in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM random effects</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-04-05-gamm-random-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-04-05-gamm-random-effects/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m working a lot with Generalized Additive Mixed Models (GAMMs) lately, and so, it seems I will be doing a small series on them as we go now. After a little feedback, I did some small alterations to the last post, hopefully it is a little easier to follow, you can read it here.
For this part I&amp;rsquo;d like to talk about random effects in mgcv::gamm as they are a little different from what I am used to from, for instance lme4 or even a standard GAM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GAMM spaghetti plots in R with ggplot</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-03-07-gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-03-07-gamm-spaghetti-plots-in-r-with-ggplot/</guid>
      <description>Here we go! Stepping into the world of blogging through R and blogdown! This is both super exciting and slightly scary, I have not really shared code online like I plan here before. But I guess we start somewhere. And we start with plotting.
A co-worker was working on some generalized additive mixed models (GAMM) through the R package mgcv. The analyses work very well, and results were as expected. There were also some built in plotting functions for the gamm output in R.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>